rblumer13@gmail.com | 630-632-9213 | Chicago, IL

GitHub | LinkedIn | Portfolio

Summary

I am a Full Stack Web Developer proficient in React, Node.js, and Git/GitHub. I have experience in education which has allowed me to develop my skills using effective verbal and written communication, collaborating in a team environment, and mediating interpersonal conflicts. I also have a strong background in music.

Skills

Front End: JavaScript, React, jQuery, Node.js, HTML5, CSS3, Git, GitHub, NPM, RESTful APIs

Back End: Node.js, Java, PostgreSQL, NPM, Express, SQL, PHP

Related: Written & verbal communication, project management, program coordinating, copywriting,

music instruction/performance

Recent Projects

Ducklings Care Diary (web-based app): Teachers record notes for the students in their class to share with parent users. Built with React, Node.is, Express, PostgreSQL. Demo | Code

Activities Assistant (web-based app): Organize and share information about enrichment activities for your school or community center. Built with React, Node.js, Express, PostgreSQL. Demo | Code

Meet the Music (web-based app): Search for upcoming concerts by date and location, then stream music from artists at your upcoming events. Built with JavaScript, jQuery, HTML5, and CSS3. Demo | Code

Education

THINKFUL December 2019

Engineering Flex

- Learned industry best practices and practical software development standards with a focus on HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, Node.js, React, Redux, and algorithms & data structures.
- Created and deployed mobile-first applications while learning new languages and frameworks by collaborating several hours every week with a senior web developer.

ILLINOIS WESLEYAN UNIVERSITY

Bachelor of Music Education (BME)

GPA: 3.74 / 4.0

Vice President of Membership: Sigma Alpha Iota, International Women's Music Fraternity (2013-2014)

- Member of Kappa Delta Pi, International Honor Society in Education
- Kincaid Scholarship: awarded to a female music education student of high caliber

Experience

BRITISH INTERNATIONAL SCHOOL OF CHICAGO, LINCOLN PARK CAMPUS

Chicago, IL March 2016 - Present

May 2014

Director of Enrichment & Choir Teacher

- Coordinated 100+ extra-curricular programs for student population of 500+ children ages 3-11
- Led team of school teachers and qualified external instructors and companies to provide diverse programs
- Created and enacted policies and procedures to ensure consistency throughout programs
- Maintained positive relationships with parents, students, and partner companies through effective verbal and written communication
- Instructed choirs and singing ensembles to perform at a variety of school and community events

LYRIC OPERA OF CHICAGO Administrative Intern & Outbound Calling Representative

Chicago, IL

September 2015 - February 2016

- Composed and edited copy for operas, recitals and concert programs
- Created and maintained organized filing system to ensure smooth office procedures for singers and management
- Sold tickets and subscriptions to opera goers by calling customers and using effective marketing strategies

CLEARVIEW ELEMENTARY SCHOOL

Waukegan, IL

K-5 General Music Teacher

August 2014 – August 2015

- Organized large community concerts to showcase students' learning and performance skills
- Instructed 300 students in grades K-5 in diverse music topics
- Led staff in common school-improvement goals by contributing to the Building Leadership Team